<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Website Programming on </title>
    <link>http://192.168.0.208:1313/categories/website-programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Website Programming on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 21:38:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://192.168.0.208:1313/categories/website-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Connect to Wi-Fi From Terminal on Ubuntu 22.04/20.04 with WPA Supplicant</title>
      <link>http://192.168.0.208:1313/blog/2023/01/connect-to-wi-fi-from-terminal-on-ubuntu-22-04-or-20.04-with-wpa-supplicant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 21:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.0.208:1313/blog/2023/01/connect-to-wi-fi-from-terminal-on-ubuntu-22-04-or-20.04-with-wpa-supplicant/</guid>
      <description>This article describes how to connect your Linux Ubuntu server to wifi, primarily if you are using a wifi adaptor card. In my example I will be connecting my W-iFi card from Gen Basic to my Lebre “Le Potato” s905x-cc single board computer server.
Le Potato &amp;ldquo;s905x-cc&amp;rdquo; GenBasic Wi-Fi Card We will be storing our Wi-Fi network and password in a wpa_supplicant configuration file. Please note that you will need an existing internet connection to install the wpa_supplicant software before connecting to Wi-Fi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different Types of Security Login Standards for Applications</title>
      <link>http://192.168.0.208:1313/blog/2023/01/types-of-auth-for-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 21:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.0.208:1313/blog/2023/01/types-of-auth-for-apps/</guid>
      <description>This article is about the different types of security standards used for logging into applications
Security Login Standards The three main standards I will focus this article on are:
HTTP Basic Auth - Least secure OAuth - More secure SAML - Most secure Despite these security standards, a single method is 100% safe. All best practices must be followed to reduce your chances as much as possible in preventing any security breaches to your websites and applications</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
